# **Norman Teodoro**

317 - 11507 84 Ave, Delta, BC, V4C 0E5 6048343158

normanteodoro@hotmail.com

#### SUMMARY

I am a software engineer who has worked in various industries having held a variety of roles like support, systems administration, and development. During that time, I've learned to cultivate my personal interests and personality to help me excel in Engineering. A multi-faceted background has allowed me to develop an expertise in working in a goal-oriented and team driven-environment.

#### RELEVANT SKILLS

#### Languages

Node.js, JavaScript, HMTL, CSS, Mongoose, React, Python, VB.Net, ASP.Net

#### Software

Databases: Postgres, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL, MS Access

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineering Fellow

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

General Assembly (Remote)

- 12 week, 480+ hour immersive study focusing on programming and computer science fundamentals as well as an array of in-demand programming languages, frameworks, and libraries.
- Project: Arcade game a game written in JavaScript and HTML5. Link to the code: https://github.com/foosasugaome/candy\_hunt
- Project: A simple stocks portfolio performance tracker. https://github.com/foosasugaome/express-finance
- Project: Inventory management software written in MERN stack. https://github.com/foosasugaome/kat-inventory-management-client
- Project: LFG Software written in MERN stack: https://boisterous-crostata-b66bd1.netlify.app/

# **Remote Support Technician**

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

F12.net

- Provided technical support to the company's clients across Canada and the United States.
- Ensured long-term trust with different clients by familiarity with a large variety of different industries, systems, software, personnel, and SOPs.
- Used a variety of MSP software such as ConnectWise, N-Central, Screen Connect, and IT Glue.

#### **Technical Support Technician**

May 2019 - Sep 2020

Commission Scolaire Marguerite-Bourgeovs

- Coordinated with the school directors regarding IT needs and issues.
- Performed troubleshooting and diagnosis for issues related to software and peripheral equipment.
- Documented the inventory and ensure its accuracy.
- Monitored and responded to tickets using C2 Atom.
- Implemented remote troubleshooting techniques to solve common software and hardware issues.

## Franchise Owner / Manager

Nov 2009 - Sep 2016

Gymboree Play & Music franchisee, Quezon City, Philippines

- Managed the day-to-day operations of the school.
- Approved and managed monthly budget and expenses.

# **Systems Analyst**

Nov 2008 - Nov 2009

Ennovation Inc., Quezon City, Philippines

- Managed the company's software development team.
- Met with clients to discuss system requirements, specifications, costs, and timeline.
- Designed and implemented systems requirements of clients.

# Senior Programmer/Analyst

Nov 2006 - Nov 2008

Paramount Life and General Insurance Corp, Makati, Philippines

- Developed web-based applications for the company.
- Maintained most of the existing web and windows-based applications.
- Evaluated and recommended hardware and software requirements.

# **IT Manager**

Aug 2004 - Nov 2006

ASA Color & Chemical Industries, Inc., Quezon City, Philippines

- Provided IT solutions, infrastructure, and support for the organization.
- Managed the company's main system application and ensured system availability.
- Ensured that IT facilities met the needs of the individuals and projects.

#### Web Developer

Nov 2009 - Sep 2016

E-Store Exchange Inc., Makati, Philippines

Developed and maintained the front-end and back-end systems of the company.

#### **EDUCATION**

# General Assembly

Apr 2022

(Remote)

Software Engineering Immersive Certificate

#### CFP Leonard da Vinci

Jun 2019

Montreal, Québec

Diploma in Educational Studies – IT Support

## **Philippine School of Business Administration**

Apr 2000

Manila, Philippines

BSBA Management Information System